welcome to the stola the stoah is a
digital campfire where equal hear and
dialogue about what matters most at the
night's edge what's happening now
[Music]
all right welcome to the stoah I'm gonna
do some check-ins I feel calm and
grounded and grateful that Ravens gonna
run the show today because I'm a little
too calm to focus on asking really good
questions that Christopher deserves to
be asked so I'm Peter Lindbergh the
steward of the stoah and the stoah is a
place for us to cohere and dialogue
about what matters most at the nice edge
of this moment and today we have
Christopher a life and Raven will do a
formal introduction on Christopher and
she'll lead the show today in the Q&A
and then they'll have a conversation
we'll have a Q&A and then we'll close it
up and if everyone's okay maybe we can
stage through maybe ten minutes after
the hour if not we can end it at the
hour if Christopher can't stay longer
that means that I'll hand it over to
emcee of the evil freedom thank you
Peter
and thank you Christopher for being here
today so Christopher life is the founder
of a new American political party one
nation and the co-creator of the Alwyn
Leadership Academy the first cohort of
the Academy graduated a few weeks ago
and I was fortunate enough to be a
member of that group
I see Christopher and other readers at
one nation doing something really bold
and unique and they're addressing
material reality and the necessity for
us to move beyond theory and actually
into practice and mobilization in order
to actually do systems change and I
wanted to bring Christopher on to the
stoah because we've been having
conversations about politics but it's
been I don't know I've found that we
don't quite know how to move forward in
a political reality and I really wanted
to talk to Christopher about the
reclamation of politics itself how can
we reorder standing of what political
action is what taking on the inheritance
of our forebears it is and stepping into
stewardship so thank you Christopher for
coming today and to talk about these
these subjects I'm really happy to be
here Ravin thank you for the invitation
yeah so I wanted to start with the
question just what is what is Alwyn
leadership and what role does it have to
play in the reclamation of our politics
I was fortunate enough about nine years
ago to have met a kind of misunderstood
very intelligent man Encinitas named
Daniels from October that most people
had never heard of the floor and he
became a very dear friend and a mentor
and I learned a lot from him before he
was ever creating content that many of
you were able to find and we work
together in multiple capacities and he
helped open up a world of thinking as
well as deeply supported my own personal
transformational process and the the
center of of all of that mentorship was
around the notion of an omni win/win
world that would require us to be Omni
considerate in order to create an omni
win/win world and so all when leadership
is nothing more than an omni
consideration and Omni win-win as -
Martin Berger would articulate it it's
just packaged in a way that's accessible
and palatable to the average person and
in a way that's not brought forward as a
technical term or a theoretical or
intellectual term but actually a
practical concept that we can each
strive to embody on a day to day basis
on a moment-to-moment basis based upon
the scales of influence that we have
available to us whether that's the one
person in front of you or a team that
you work with an organization or if you
find yourself with a larger capacity of
influence over that domain that you have
influence over in service to
us positively impacting all beings that
were able to have influence over and
when is a technical term which I refer
to as the augmentation of choices so for
someone to win is for them to win more
choices for someone to lose is to lose
choices so win isn't just a a conceptual
notion that that doesn't really have a
grounding rod actually has a very very
specific grounding rod which is that
that augmentation of choice so to live
all win to be all win to be an all when
leader is to live on a moment-to-moment
basis with the intent and hopefully the
capacity to follow through with that
intent to some degree of efficacy to be
expanding the choices of those that were
impacting and forced landries quo which
I'm sure many of you are familiar with
is love is that which enables choice so
we talked about Winnie and we talked
about the augmentation of choice we're
actually talking about a very practical
manifestation of love in the world and
it's very powerful it almost rips open
themes of our previous concept of love
and of love and reality where love moves
from this notion of an attractive force
to this this fierce force of an abling
choice and then you know what we've
previously called love gets words like
affinity and gets words like attraction
it gets words like romance it gets words
like all these other things but love
love is this force that expands the
choices of those that are around us from
from the direct people we influence all
the way to people that we care about
not that we in people who care about
that we might not directly know all the
way to life animals plants etc etc so to
be an all when leader is to want to show
up in a way that is opening up the
choice
of people across the world and
throughout time and that is a very
sophisticated thing to orient to that's
why we call it an ideal that we aspire
to you don't have to know that every
single choice you make is going to
positively influence the expansion of
choice of all beings throughout all time
but why not aspire to that why not why
not use that as a as an ideal to
practice and to vet your own choices
against and when you get feedback that
your choice is actually undermined the
choice of others why not use that as a
way to realize that you're out of
integrity with your embodiment of that
ideal and have that positive feedback
loop and what would the world be like if
hundreds of us thousands of us millions
of us had this positive feedback with of
perpetually calibrating to our ability
to be expanding the choices that others
have available to them mm-hmm yeah how
do you feel like we can inspire people
into this like kind of deep reverence
and understanding of the significance of
taking those types of actions it seems
like many of us are kind of at an
impasse where even if we do and have an
impulse to do something we haven't quite
realized what right relationship with
that impulse would be and then there's
many people who have just completely
written off that type of action because
the particular manifestations of
politics that we see today are degra
gating I think what what politics could
be and I'm kind of curious like how do
you think that we can draw that type of
inspiration out of people well I feel
like life is do you mean the vast
majority of the initiating which is good
news because that's a tough one to be
responsible for raise
the conscience of others but what the
way that I feel like we play with a lot
of conscious co-creators with life
herself is to help to crystallize the
consciousness as its raison is as
emerging so that people can ground what
they're experiencing as their awareness
expands and so I think that having terms
like all win and all in for all life and
having bodies of work around both of
those things and I I do happen to have
an unpublished book called all in for a
life another one called Alwyn both those
will likely be coming out this year
then then you help to crystallize this
consciousness as that then allow us to
orient around it more intentionally it
allows us to think about and contemplate
it and hold ourselves accountable to
these standards it helps us to give us
an overt domain to practice amongst our
communities so it just kind of gives us
this context to intentionally cultivate
that way of being and I feel like that's
that that's a role that I have to play
and that we can all play and when people
are feeling wow yeah I I want to create
a world that works for all I want my
actions to actually be loving in the
sense that they're their expanding
choice in improving the quality of our
human society or human civilization and
now where do I start well we have we
call our five steps or five stages or
five principles of Alwyn leadership
which is a type fractal of a path that
is relevant at the scale of a moment and
it's also relevant at the scale of a
career and at many scales in between so
it's this kind of a whole onic
expandable protocol that we offer all
when leaders to help them to orient to
all in action and and what that looks
like is step number one is know yourself
so understand yourself again at the
scale of a moment this is one of my
thoughts one of my feelings you know
what what what is my experience of being
ten minutes late to this recorded thing
that I thought was starting to love him
is actually starting at 10 and like what
is that experience for me in a moment
all the way to in a macro sense knowing
yourself your skills your shadows your
capacities your aspirations your visions
like really knowing yourself and I
believe you need to actually know
yourself to a certain degree of solidity
and security before you're capable of
setting a perspective aside and then
being able to get into perspective
enough of another in order to know
another and so the second step then is
to they know each other and have a
commitment to be able to interact with
and participate in a subjective
experience of others so we can really
connect to their world see the world
from their perspective understand what
matters to them what their pains are
what their aspirations are how they
perceive reality and that moves us into
a relationship it gets us into
collective intelligence because
collective intelligence is really the
interpenetration of our subjective
experiences able to wire together as a
as a super collective so we need to know
ourselves and know each other in order
to experience that collective
intelligence and then that positions us
to better know the world because the
world itself is massively complex
there's more to know about any aspect of
the world that anyone will ever know but
through collective intelligence we can
better metabolize what is so see the
world from different perspectives does
that one of those spiritual things we
can do is proactively pursue diverse
perspectives and one of the reasons for
that is because that enables us to have
a better understanding of reality
because the more diverse perspectives we
can look at reality through the more
different facets we're gonna see and
understand and therefore the better
we're gonna understand reality and the
more that we understand how reality is
first just how we think reality might be
the more effective we are to take action
that's actually useful to the whole and
so that know the world then leads the
fourth step which is to run all in
experiments because it's not all win
isn't something you can will
Alwyn isn't necessarily a direct act of
volition Alwyn is a context you've set
up for yourself the experiment within
and then you learn through the feedback
loops and the results of what you
generate and produced actually verify
what actually was Omni considerate what
was actually was Omni win-win B because
it's only through touching an idea of
what might be Alwyn to reality itself to
that touchstone of reality and in
getting that feedback that you actually
find out what did or didn't work in the
way the envision might be so so we we
collapse all in action into fully
contextualized by all in experimentation
so we're just constantly taking
experiments because if we connect to
ourselves each other and the world then
it's gonna naturally give us ideas on
new possibilities I mean convert those
ideas into experiments and that to me
experiment again that you can run in a
moment which is it which is that which
is a humble form of action because you
know there's like confidence behind that
action as though this is the thing
that's going to work but it's a play off
of a line from the daodejing where Lao
Tzu says the Masters walk through life
as though they're walking across a
frozen brook so that's this kind of like
well I don't really know but I think and
I'm confident gonna take an action i I
put my confidence behind my capacity to
generate experiments in a moment small
basis I and in relationship with the
feedback loops of life to verify what
actually worked and so we run that cycle
of know yourself know each other know
the world run all in experiments and
then the fifth pillars is is empower
other Alwyn leaders which is basically
the thing I talked about at the very
beginning which is initiating this
crystallization of consciousness of
people who are one team to experience
their own all in leadership and if you
run those five steps then something is
going to start to emerge and you're
gonna start to do things that are what I
call creating paradise because because
to do something that's all win is to
open up a
beautiful possibility that was that that
wasn't actualized yet it opens up
something new and I caught all that
opening in Paradise choice gets opened
up quality of life gets opened up new
possibilities get opened up and so as
all with leaders we become Paradise
makers and we want to make paradise the
scale of our household gonna make
paradise the scale of the entire
collective of humanity and I guess
that's what circles back around the
conversation around politics which I'm
happy to actually jump right into that
element unless you'd like to ask them a
question or go somewhere else go ahead
yeah I've been appropriate time to just
circle back around with that final piece
around the reclamation of politics
mm-hmm though as an almond leader
devoted to creating paradise at every
scale we can possibly influence then we
have to have a real serious conversation
around power and power is a topic that I
don't I don't cycle in all the game be
conversations although I care
tremendously about it just not the space
that I spend I don't read the content or
watch the content but I don't I don't
hear that this notion of power is really
a central concept but but it's a
critical concept or so power is the
ability to achieve an intention thanks
Alexa oh the power is this ability to
achieve an outcome and so if we want to
create a more beautiful world that our
heart knows as possible we have to take
this power conversation extremely
seriously and it's right for us to
desire to become more powerful right in
some ways power itself has been
something that's been polarized against
or it's been it's been attributed to
those who abuse power as powerful
therefore we don't want to be like them
therefore it's not good to pursue power
desire to be powerful but I invite all
of us to reclaim power and to realize
that we can't achieve our vision
of a recreated transformed human
civilization without becoming extremely
powerful and and politics and government
I'm gonna say government not politics
government is in a lot of ways the most
effective harnessing of power that
humans have ever created
right this ability to to tax and
generate public resources this is the
ability to create laws that actually
directly influence the how society
operates the operating system of society
and civilization and most importantly
the the this the crux of the power the
government holds is its legitimate or
legal use over violence the government
has the legal ability to physically do
something to you if you do or don't
comply with its policies it also has the
legitimate or legal use of being able to
inflict violence unilaterally upon other
countries or other actors it also has
the budgets to be able to augment the
capacity to inflict violence in profound
persistent abilities so this power is
extremely important and if we aren't
realizing how powerful this power is of
government and realizing the necessity
to steward it from the conscious of all
win then then all when aspirants are
going to always be relegated to zoom
calls and festivals and very small
intentional communities while those who
pursue power will be able to wield power
in service to perpetuating a win-lose
world so so politics isn't government
and politics is definitely not vying or
manipulating
or line like we typically think politics
is the stewardship of our home
politics is saying I have a vision for
how our world can be better and taking
action consistently and and and being
susceptible to rest personal harm in
service to fulfilling that vision of a
better collective that we can be a part
of and that we can offer to our children
to inherit that we leave for them and so
so this is a political moment that we're
having starting a company is as an
active politics
organized and intentional community is
an act of politics right in a book that
you believe will improve the quality of
life for others as not to politics
politics is this energy that creates the
best world possible and so a full
reclamation of politics is to connect
the the nobility of this notion of
caring for and stuarti this tangible
reality that we inhabit with each other
and we can't fully be in our political
leadership without realizing what a
critical dimension of reality government
is so politics and government go hand at
hand because government is the is the
institutional infrastructure that our
ancestors passed down to us that we then
now are inheriting as a way to exert our
political will
so in insane this I'm not saying that
government is good as it is or that
there's not profound transformations and
what we currently call government in
order to actually unlock a new era of
humanity defined by something that we
can call gov
where the structures and the
consciousness the paradigms the
mechanisms of our government are
completely on the chopping block for
profound recreation transformation but
I'm not affirming the validity of the
current structure of government by
talking about a reclamation of
government and politics I'm saying that
we don't have the ability and will never
have the ability nor the right nor
should we to be able to invent the
future of governance without first
inheriting the government that our
ancestors created for us to inherit and
it's like improv comedy where the way
that you create the next scene is by yes
anding the previous scene so if you're
on it in stand-up comedy troupe it's not
cool at all to think that what your
partner just said before you was stupid
because that energy is gonna drain the
energy of that comedy troupe but if you
yes and what happened before then it
buys you the currency to inform where
the scene goes from here just an
ultimate play of yes and in the past
that's led to this moment in time so
that we actually qualify to be able to
create what happens next so that right
there is politics governmental
stewardship and Alwyn leadership all
bundled together and living this way the
integration of all of these concepts
that I'm sharing is what I call all win
political culture and and that's
something that I'm devoted to spending
my life generating and sharing and
proliferating Alwyn political culture
and the creation of one nation as a
political party is an instantiation of
Alwyn political culture the
because we need to have we need to both
get into practice of our theories and so
we have to create our theories right so
all in political culture is the theory
one nation is the context that we're
creating to practice that and then the
life 2020 campaign which is my
presidential campaign which really is
just getting warmed up I think it's
gonna get interesting soon is isn't
another it attend my embodiment of all
in political culture and just to land a
doozie as a last kind of peace on this
is that the proactive cultivation of all
in political culture coming together in
community and creating concepts and
practices and information that we can
cycle amongst each other and rituals and
accountability is that proactive pursuit
of all when political culture is what I
call all win political religion and so
it's this invitation to walk the path of
all in political religion to embody all
win political culture to become a
paradise creator at all scales Wow
well could you talk a little bit about
what what religion means in that context
so the way that I define religion is
going back to the Latin root of the word
and it has several different
etymological connotations and one of
those is to bind together another of
those is a sense of obligation
another is is a sense of care in
practice and another connotation is to
cultivate some theme through repetition
these are four different Latin
etymological connotations of the word
religion so when I use the word religion
I'm referring to that which binds us
together connects
to a shared sense of obligation that
brings forward our care to embody
something through rapid repeated
practice so anything that does that is
what I call religion wonderful we've got
some really great questions coming in
the chat now so I think we'll move over
to some of the Q&A and yeah if anybody
has any questions they can put them in
the chat and if Greg has questions you
should just unmute yourself and go ahead
and indicate that you want to ask one
and don't have to worry about the chat
obviously so we'll begin with more it
Moritz Morty's question I have okay yeah
you did say something but maybe it was
in response to I was just commenting on
other people's comments and questions
okay oh yes so you were commenting on
Jacob Jacob would you like to begin
oh well I I'm always a little reluctant
cuz I'm I feel like I'm sort of by
default just adversarial but I promise I
mean it politely and have all the best
intention bring it on up and I can like
toggle to look just a nice guy to it
hopefully so I guess I'm I feel like
we're talking about here's my big
question I have several but here's the
big one I guess if we're talking so much
on me I feel like the way we can
actually put it into practice right now
like this very second cuz we're us we're
all sort of anxious to actually start
doing it and we love talking about a bit
maybe we are doing it but shouldn't we
do it where every time we get together
we do nothing but it's always just
conversations okay we're not just
listening to one person because I feel
like that there's a sort of I think
there's a
to that format that I feel and I could
be wrong about that - like I'm dying for
this to be nothing but conversations and
then we'd be actually doing the Omni in
real time another question for myself or
for the host I don't know I didn't have
a target audience I guess for that all
who care to listen or require suppose I
feel that's a good point actually for
Christopher to go into because it's an
actual power dynamic that's at play and
so maybe you want to answer that yeah I
mean I think power is great I think
power dynamics are great and I think
that it's important for people to
consciously opt into them so if the the
folks that are holding this field
clearly indicated the format and you
clearly and that was the format the day
generated by their vision of how to
create value for you did not
feels really beautiful if they
manipulated you in any particular way
and and led you to believe that this
experience be different than it is then
then that's something that we could
obviously look at and if there's
something that you crave Jacob that's
different than what the stoah is
creating for you and that can actually
be an indicator that there's an act of
leadership for you that's emerging
inside of you to create something that's
exactly perfectly gripped to the vision
that you have of of an ideal experience
and that's not polarizing against this
moment it's just actually using this
moment to create a little contrast
springboard that shows oh holy smokes I
have an idea of creating something that
doesn't yet exist and then you might go
and create that and you might find the
the pros and the cons of the ideal that
you hold it for yourself and you might
actually find yourself creating
something totally transformational or
you might find yourself circling all the
way back and crazy
very similar to this momentous
experience once you experiment out
yourself but it sounds like that active
that that inspiration is is inviting you
to create what you want to experience
yeah great thank you and then we have
engine engine would you like to ask your
question hey Christopher my question is
just that it's almost like I can't
sometimes see what you're staying
because there's so many connotates and
conditions and associations that
conjured up by words like power and
government and monopoly over
I think people the chat brought great
points that maybe that is something you
just have to accept if not a firm and
kind of move forward if that's the first
point to get to I'm wondering if you're
thinking about using different words or
things like that that can kind of better
get your point across without the
historical baggage yeah this is
something I kind of face and I'm not
sure what the path forward is a path
that I choose although I'm not sure that
it's the most effective path with
reflections like this but I'm probably
gonna keep choosing it because I it
feels right to me is to shamelessly use
terms that have this type of historical
baggage in order to kind of light the
fire of the historical baggage
underneath it kind of like an alchemical
flame to then like burn off the
connotations that actually have created
a sense of separation from it I don't
want to play in to that separation I
would play into people belief that
politics and government are inherently
futile or immovable or things like that
I don't want to play into the way that
we've polarized from our own sense of
power in like reflected relationship to
us polarizing the
power in the world so I I kind of have a
sick enjoyment of using terms that make
people feel uncomfortable and then
staying with them in that to notice
what's actually coming up because
ultimately this is about integration and
we can't do what we want to do without
integrating all these different parts of
ourselves in full wholeness and
government and politics and politicians
and power and military and police and
bureaucracy if you believe I don't know
that you do but if you do believe that
we're all one and that we're actually
all one interconnected field and maybe
we're actually our individual node of
consciousness is emerging from a greater
collective field of consciousness and
planet of which humanity is a part of
then all these different things are you
right the government is you and the
bureaucracy is you and and the people
work at the DMV are you and and it's all
you and so to accept these things
without trying to kind of like dance
around them is to proactively embrace
the parts of our greater shared
collective that is us with like without
any filters so that's something that I
am personally really inspired to
continue doing I'm curious if that
response was meaningful to you or if you
ever need to follow up thoughts on the
topic because the question you're asking
is a very good and important one yeah I
don't think I have cogent thoughts but
you got me thinking about a lot of stuff
if I could offer one trivial thing that
came up is it makes me think it's
incredibly important that you have time
because I just realized if you only had
30 seconds to talk to me or two minutes
I probably just pattern match you to
like another politician saying cool
stuff and saying about changing this and
that but it's only when you have the
chance to kind of go into it and explain
yourself that I'm like oh he's different
um so I'm I don't know if that matters
but I came in mind yeah why is Joe Rogan
the most famous and most loved
Kaster because he has actual long
conversations with people and and Anya I
would ask for your partnership I have a
lot to say there's a lot coming through
with one nation there's a lot coming
through the like 2020 campaign there's a
lot coming through with some these books
that are coming out and maybe there's a
role of leadership that you can play to
help to create that space and time for
other people to be able to receive the
potency and transformational
implications of the message that I bring
forward because you might relate to
people and have that trust in place and
then can serve as some type of a bridge
so every single like idea that we have
is some way a reflection of some form of
leadership that we can step into in a
body so I really love to reflect back
those those ideas because because
there's a deep sense of power when we
realize some way the world could be
better like let's just say the idea on
you that Christopher life has enough
time for people to receive the depth of
the profundity he's offering and to
perceive that and then to realize wait a
second I can create that reality and
then you go in and create that reality
and then you have a greater sense of
dignity and personal power that you can
actually fill the gap between anything
you perceive as how the world could be
and the actions that you take to make
the world that way
you
Peter do you want to ask your question
Thank You Raven so let me go up or is it
okay I'll say my memory what do you
think about training power literacy
before pursuing actual power because I
do agree with you there's like this lot
of communities there's a sort of felt
sense and and kind of gesturing towards
power is bad but you know in order to
get anything done we need to have power
or at least a power to get something
done but how do we not get seduced by
the trappings of power or the
pathological versions of power once we
start getting more power yeah thank you
Peter for that question and that's
exactly where all wind comes in so a
commitment to all it and based upon the
framework around it and then
accountability to one's self around that
and it being in a community practice of
other people and a public statement of
the standard of all wind leadership that
we who are gaining power are committed
to being held accountable so we're
constantly getting feedback loops and
receiving the information from those
feedback loops of how we can calibrate
in a more refined way into that all wind
way of being and again all win
references the expansion of choice
expanding of choice references love and
so what we're actually talking about is
having a overt practical tangibly
relevant commitment to love that then is
the context and the consciousness by
which we deploy our power so that's the
integration of love and power that that
you'll hear me talk about often as well
and so again that that's that's only
going to be based upon the degree to
which a person is holding themselves
accountable to their own commitment of
however if you just fast forward several
years or several decades or several
generations if we've normalized love as
this and then love and all win kind of
become synonyms then you know buying
organic food didn't used to be a thing
until a couple decades ago and then you
like normalize it and I've got a stamp
but now everyone can buy organic food
and you can add this some amount of
optics into the the you know the the
manufacturing process of the foods that
you eat when we normalize love and
create standards around it for our
organizational leaders or community
leaders our governmental leaders then
then raising this is no normalization
accountability around love that then we
check power it gets and I I do believe
that we could create a future scenario
where love and power are deeply
integrated and the mechanisms of
civilization prevent people from
accessing increased levels of power if
they haven't manifested a consistent
embodiment of increased levels of love
and a follow-up question I really like
that like tethering this pursuit of
power with love so they're sort of like
it's anchored by it and they're just
turn by even if I'm pronouncing the
right path ah cracy about the people who
currently get power or sociopaths
Psychopaths all the type of stuff so it
selects for it and that's the power
that's not anchored in love yeah and so
when you now it's like hey we're coming
to get some power and then how do you
not get on these people's radars so they
just squash it like a bug I think you
have to build a true prolific embodied
social movement that can withstand the
attempts of squashing this moment these
relationships let's say I gain a little
bit of power and that what there's like
stages of squashing right the first was
kind of like
slander and defamation and you know lies
and stuff like that so if tomorrow a
whole bunch if I a whole bunch stuff
comes out about a bunch of misconduct
that that I've been you know accused of
that you don't feel matches the
experience that we had and that you're
willing to investigate if that's true or
not rather than just accepted through
poor sense making in capacities then
then that moment Peter were you you
questioned if that news bulletin was
true would be a manifestation that we
sidestep some of the squashing effect
because of the of the community the
relationships and social mood that were
building
well thank you excellent and I wanna I
want to get to maybe's thoughts and then
back to Jacob so maybe would you like to
unmute yourself ask a question uh yeah
my question was just about like I am
really sympathetic to the idea that
there's like a huge power structure and
ignoring it is not going to like amount
to the same thing as reclaiming that
power
I'm just wondering how you intend to do
something different
once you've reclaims the power so that
we don't run into the same pitfalls and
those like well-worn paths of corruption
that seem to happen when big revolutions
are like quote unquote successful yeah
at the at the structural
transformational level or at the
transformation of our political
structures that that provides the answer
to your question we have a set of a
platform of how to upgrade our democracy
that makes our democracy less accessible
to abuse of power so there's a profound
increase of transparency which that
alone just eliminates the ability for
public office to be used for abuse of
power to a substantial degree we're
talking about transformation of sense
making processes
how decision-making is transformed from
from the vote to the conversation right
so the vote is basically like a form of
warfare that's nonviolent so I get votes
and you get votes and whoever gets the
most votes wins whether it's a policy
issue or an electoral issue D of
democracy is the conversation and the
experiment not the propaganda and the
vote well I just get frozen there we go
they got froze for a second so that new
currency of a politics is doesn't allow
for the same type of manipulated
systemically corruptive powers and
forces a massive disclosure initiative
to reveal the truth of the collusion
corruption and carnage that our
political systems of the past's have
generated and are responsible for to
increase the the the the competence of
the electorate focusing on civic
empowerment and civic engagement so that
citizens and voters and people that are
participating in our republic are
themselves more less more anti fragile
against manipulation so we it's a whole
Renaissance of civic engagement that
happens at the structural level of how
our governments work all the way down to
the prioritization level of how we
empower people to better steward our
governments if people don't rise in to a
higher level of political responsibility
then we are completely screwed there's
no solution where some legal
transformation or technological
transformation is going to save us it's
not until each of us feel that sense of
political responsibility where we say
the
city is my city the state is my state
this country is my country this world is
my world
I am fully responsible for everything
that happens here whatever happens here
that I don't prefer happens on my watch
and I'm responsible for that and I will
take action around that until we're able
to get there in our hearts and our minds
in our embodiment all of our systems
will still be able to be manipulated I
could get into office and change 30
different laws and policies that
transform and upgrade our democratic
systems but if those aren't maintained
by this Renaissance of civic engagement
then they'll be futile and they'll be
undone so ultimately this comes back to
the cultural movement this comes back
the social movement we have to realize
that by letting our hands off of the
wheel we have created a win-lose world
with piles of carnage that should be
unbearable for us to actually comprehend
and that the only way that we get not
that is by a higher level of political
responsibility
I accidentally ders yeah as our leaders
- to use our platform of leadership to
challenge people to rise in that
responsibility as opposed to
manipulating them and lying to them and
disempowering them and polarizing
themselves from the sense of
responsibility and saying listen great
I'm your elected leader hold me
accountable do this do that do that like
that's like the greatest act of
achieving that world is for our leaders
to demand a higher level of
accountability from their own
constituents
excellent thanks for that question may
be and so I think we're gonna bring in
our last question here Jacob would you
like to share your thoughts
I've sit so much I feel like I know they
actually continue in voice here but so I
think the big my big my whopper I guess
is sort of is this hominy win win
ideology stuff just like the most
advanced form of equality of outcome
which I'm assuming most of us aren't
fans of right because it's homogenizing
and it's ultimately like just destroys
life right the quality of outcome stuff
and it just seems like this is just that
and I like saying it's that on the
sports drink for some reason that's
funny but so let's see how that's is it
worth asking that question isn't that
question when you say quality outcome
can you just open that up a little bit
I'm not familiar that is a technical
term come on well I guess I can just
refer to like I guess for most people
just think maybe just refer to JP cuz
he's you know Jordan Peterson he's the
one it's it's sort of expressed it the
best right like arguably and so call you
out come this equity idea that we all
have a sort of oh man like don't that's
such a big question to ask you can I
don't think you can turn the table that
widely on me can someone else maybe give
them a short version of equality of
outcome I feel I can I do it in under
five minutes
I'll find bridge I mean equality of
outcome is the idea that we are
obligated with our civic and
governmental structure to assure an
equal come for each citizen that they
have an equal set of living they have
equal money etc sort of access to all
things equally and that's a deeply
flawed idea for many people because that
you can never you can never guarantee
that and it tends to require use of
power that actually squash this
difference that also this allows people
who are expressing their different
valuation of what they really care about
in life and then there's the other which
is equality of opportunity and so I
think what Jacob is asking about is
whether what you are talking about with
Omni then is a sort of souped-up higher
fidelity or sort of
concepts version of equality about does
that do you justice Jacob yeah I think
that's a big part of it a big part of it
but it's also has a lot to do with what
we what how we decide what competence is
right because if you have ten people in
your cabinet right let's say in five of
them are female and five or more male
than you are saying that's the that's a
good scenario but you haven't really
measured the the ability of those
individuals based on any real competence
just on their gender in that case okay
so that's it that's a big part of that
that's why it's a really big it's a
really big definition actually it's what
we you'd handled a big part of it really
well so yeah let me jump off real quick
to finish this with Lachlan and Maurice
I'm gonna use your definition as my jump
off point I think based upon that
definition that Alwyn is the integral
um and quality of opportunity because
winning itself is contextualized by the
choices that a person wants to have
available to them that aren't currently
available to them so there's a
recalibration of that outcome
contextualized by an individual's
aspiration and that's what makes it
winning for them and so what we want to
do is we want to create a context of our
consciousness and of our political
systems that is not because because the
quality of opportunity I think without
the quality of outcome thing is probably
and again I haven't studied this body of
work but I'm guessing that the argument
of the shadow side is that that kind of
points to maybe our current capitalistic
systems and how that quality of
opportunity can potentially be abused
and and lead to people not having shared
results because maybe you know there's
there's there's power dynamics that
enable people to abuse that quality of
opportunity so if you bring that
together then you want everyone to be
able to want everyone else to be able to
win according to their own definition of
winning and while that may sound
idealistic I actually believe that's
what paradise is paradise is an embodied
experience of everyone else wanting
everyone else to expand their choice
based upon the choices that they want to
have the ability to have access to so
that's I think that we're in the zone of
integrating the outcome and the and the
opportunity piece
great Thank You Christopher I would
invite you to share any final words or
statements that you would like to draw
with us maybe tell us what's next for
Alwyn or for one nation what's on the
horizon oh yeah great so one nations new
political party got a couple members of
the local party on the call here and so
it's a it is itself a complex adaptive
system right so if if the world that
it's causing us some problems is a
complex adaptive system of win-lose
dynamics that are basically screwing us
in every conceivable way then we need
our own complex adaptive system to
respond to that complex adaptive system
so as a political party we have the
capacity to organize a large quantity of
people to be able to work on all sectors
and all domains to develop new patterns
and templates that inform how our
redesigned Alwyn human civilization
while having the political power to move
people into positions of local regional
and national governmental stewardship to
be able to implement those patterns in
those contexts according to their own
you know leadership capacities in that
moment so having a field of thousands of
leaders stewarding government at all
different scales implementing a slew of
transformational policies that result in
deep societal transformation is the
affordance that organized new political
party gives us so that seems relevant so
we're doing that so you're welcome to go
to one nation party I would love for you
to read the our website we have like
eight pages under learn more that
articulate the the kind of premise Khan
steps of our theory of change that and I
either to read if that inspires you and
about you to register as a member of one
nation again
registering of one nation is is the full
cycle of let's say used to be a
political activist and then you realize
that that's never gonna get the job done
and then so you became just heartened
and you came like a alienated and jaded
and realized I'll never do that again
but then you realize that you're not
actually exerting your your own power
and you're not actually being
responsible for these systems now you're
like well where do I go from here well
you you register as a member of one
nation that's how you complete that that
cycle in that process of reconnecting to
activism and political stewardship we
are we have a policy research
organization called civilization
redesign so if you're working on any
templates or patterned or policies you
could apply to be a fellow of
civilization redesign and and and and
and benefit from certain types of
support infrastructure referring to our
civilization redesigned fellows and
we're moving our headquarters from San
Diego to New Mexico and we just leased a
40 acre property and we're building a
collaborative village to steward to
house the next stage of the mission so
we can bring several dozen full-time
collaborators in to be a fully embodied
actualized community of practice
practicing the principles of all in
leadership while practically building
one nation as a political party as well
as creating maximum exposure for the
life 2020 campaign as well as other
initiatives of social movement building
so if you're inspired by that you can go
to as your village dot one Thank You
Maurice for putting that link in there
if you go to the bottom of that page
there's a little blurb that invites you
into our info session which is going to
be tomorrow evening at 5:30 Pacific time
and you're invited to come for an hour
and a half and learn more about Azure
village and
possibility you actually come in there
for several months and being a part of
this community of practice and helping
us to further these systemically
transformational political initiatives
while practicing the Alwyn embodiment so
party civilization redesign of course if
you're a funder you're welcome to
contribute to civilization redesign or
one nation party financially if that
inspires you and just if you're not on
the email list go to one nation dot
party and opt-in so you can stay inside
of that communication flow and you know
we're we're in this all the way through
I've I've committed to two decades of
full dedication to building and Africa
light as in one nation as far as it
possibly can go based upon our theory of
change and any of you that feel resonant
I invite you on a multi-year multi
decade journey with us because it's
going to take that time and energy and
consistency to be able to build this
complex adaptive system that has the
ability to have a profound impact on
transforming our world and I invite your
partnership on that journey
thank you Thank You Christopher thanks
for coming and thank you for your
flexibility I just so appreciate it and
thank you for opening up this this
conversation at the stoah and there's a
lot of excitement about us maybe
bringing you back or doing another event
about about this type of thing so it
we'll see you again sometime
thank you so much for the invitation is
a pleasure to be here and I really
appreciate each of you for listening
and also for your really great questions
in dialogue excellent all right Peter
take us away awesome thanks again
Christopher Thank You Raven for the
emceeing and everyone for their
excellent questions upcoming events we
have one this today at 4:00 p.m. Eastern
Time with Benjamin Boyce and it's on
gender transition and discourse RCP on
the website tomorrow we have two cool
events one with your boy Christopher
Daniels Mach number gur at 7:00 p.m.
converting mawla to sit or converting
Moloch from SIF to Jedi as if both
sociopaths and power and stuff like that
that's gonna be really really cool and
maybe gray has a cool event at 12 p.m.
Eastern Time
maybe do you want to just jump off and
say what kind of the topic is um yeah
sure I'm gonna be talking it's more a
little bit around the only fans where
you that's been going on and maybe
talking about what that says about how
we're handling the sex and kovat crisis
combination talking about how dating
apps and hookup culture have been
affecting us and how we might be able to
like steal and seduce our romance lives
back from these like big nameless
corporations that are you know taking
something that's very personal and using
it for profit and and maybe not always
actually helping us with it that much so
I'm really excited to maybe did these
stigmatize our longing a little bit
celebrate that we still want to be
connected even though we're facing some
barriers to that right now and just have
a good chat about what's alive for us in
our sexualities right now beautiful I
love how you looked in the steel and
seduced motto there you've done your
homework
maybe here so the stoah musical artistry
to the way
say to the store dossier for more
information on the upcoming events sign
up for the mailing list and you can
check out the gift economy at the end
alright everyone thank you so much I
know there's a zoom link someone posted
so if you want to continue this
conversation it's copy and paste you can
jump off that and join Jacob and the
rest